<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-07-27T15:49:41+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Chaingateway.io - Blockchain API</title><subtitle>Chaingateway.io is a blockchain saas platform that provides a suite of tools for developers to build and deploy blockchain applications. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Role Of Blockchain Apis In Unlocking Blockchain Interoperability</title><link href="/blog/role-of-blockchain-apis-in-unlocking-blockchain-interoperability/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Role Of Blockchain Apis In Unlocking Blockchain Interoperability" /><published>2023-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/role-of-blockchain-apis-in-unlocking-blockchain-interoperability</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/role-of-blockchain-apis-in-unlocking-blockchain-interoperability/"><![CDATA[<p>While the blockchain was created as a decentralized network of peers, individual blockchain networks are not open. However, the advent of blockchain API will be crucial to unlocking blockchain interoperability and mass adoption.
Thus far, there has been little incentive to change how traditional systems work. However, the unique characteristics of blockchains could speed up the adoption of new systems, which are more efficient with a reasonable investment. Making the blockchain more interoperable via APIs will speed its adoption in real-world use cases.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-blockchain-interoperability">What is Blockchain Interoperability?</h2>
<p>Blockchain interoperability is the wide array of methods that allow blockchains to communicate and work more effectively. Most blockchains are not built to be interoperable. No matter how many features a blockchain might have, the transactions are meant to occur within one network.
In the simplest terms, interoperability is the freedom to exchange data. One issue that arises when discussing interoperability is trust. If an asset leaves a network, it becomes difficult to trust its validity. Each blockchain has a consensus mechanism that it uses to validate data. True interoperability will entail blockchains being able to understand and process the authenticity of data from different chains.
While it may seem obvious that blockchains should be designed to be interoperable, it rarely happens. However, blockchain APIs are working to meet the challenge as the benefits of interoperability become obvious.
It is not the first time interoperability challenges have threatened to stifle technology adoption. The World Wide Web today would not have been possible without extensive interoperability solutions. Without various interoperability solutions, people would need hundreds of browsers to open websites and numerous operating systems on one device to use different apps. However, various innovations in interoperability have made it possible for the web to be accessible on just one device.
One important solution came in the form of the W3C Consortium. Over the years, it has created common standards enabling various ecosystems to interact and operate in a common language. The semantics created by the W3C have been crucial to speaking a common language on the internet.
Due to these common standards, the possibilities of the internet are endless. Blockchain APIs will have a similar role in the mass adoption of blockchain technology. They will enable different ecosystems to communicate and share data, leading to new use cases. Consequently, it will promote mass adoption.</p>
<h2 id="the-current-state-of-blockchain-technology">The Current State of Blockchain Technology</h2>
<p>One of the main facts about blockchain today is that no single protocol will become dominant. Instead, blockchain protocols will have to become interoperable. In the enterprise space, a few front runners have emerged: Corda and Hyperledger Fabric. However, in the public blockchain space, things are more fragmented.
In short, one blockchain network will not emerge that can meet all the needs of the different use cases possible using the technology. Instead, the industry will comprise many networks, each fulfilling a niche need. One possible outcome is that data from private networks are routed to other networks without achieving one-on-one integration. Blockchain APIs will be crucial in this role. They are needed to move data across blockchains without creating a new market for intermediaries.</p>
<h2 id="the-role-of-blockchain-apis-in-interoperability">The Role of Blockchain APIs in Interoperability</h2>
<p>Interoperability of blockchains can be accomplished by ensuring the smooth transfer of data across different chains. The transfer occurs across APIs, designed to help systems communicate with each other. A Blockchain API is a well-established tool that does not have any specialized blockchain programming knowledge to use.
APIs are flexible and expedient. However, they require one-on-one integration between networks, which can be inefficient if incorrectly handled. Additionally, they require some negotiation between platforms.
One issue with implementing blockchain APIs is that they do not require cross-platform checks. As such, unauthenticated data can be sent from one blockchain mechanism to another. One way to avoid this is by creating data standards. The standards must be based on a common organizing principle for interoperability at scale. Once such as standard is established, interoperability will speed up.</p>
<h2 id="interoperability-best-practices">Interoperability Best Practices</h2>
<p>One of the best solutions to blockchain interoperability would be the creation of common standards and the creation of a network of networks structure. After that, networks could converge around it. In existing industries that aim to adopt the blockchain, creating a neutral working group will establish common standards. Such a model would also need to support cross-chain validation of transactions.
In general, the right implementation is crucial to the success of blockchain interoperability. To solve the interoperability challenges, not only technology issues will have to be solved but governance issues as well. Additionally, data ownership and commercial business models will need to be considered.
While blockchain APIs offer the technological solution to interoperability, a series of interconnected topics need to be considered. Solving these other issues will help create a holistic approach to the mass adoption of blockchain technology.</p>
<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>Interoperability powered by blockchain APIs will improve the productivity of the entire blockchain industry. It will allow users to move assets and data across networks fast, increasing flexibility for the masses. Instead of being tied to one network, smart contracts can run on multiple chains and oracles, which submit real-world data across various platforms. When combined with the inherent benefits of decentralization, interoperability will act as the basis for the widespread adoption of the blockchain.</p>]]></content><author><name>Chaingateway</name></author><category term="Blockchain" /><category term="API" /><category term="Web3" /><category term="Blockchain APIs" /><category term="DApps" /><category term="Smart Contracts" /><category term="Web3" /><category term="Web3 Future" /><category term="Decentralized Web" /><category term="Blockchain Interoperability" /><category term="Interoperability" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[While the blockchain was created as a decentralized network of peers, individual blockchain networks are not open. However, the advent of blockchain API will be crucial to unlocking blockchain interoperability and mass adoption. Thus far, there has been little incentive to change how traditional systems work. However, the unique characteristics of blockchains could speed up the adoption of new systems, which are more efficient with a reasonable investment. Making the blockchain more interoperable via APIs will speed its adoption in real-world use cases. What is Blockchain Interoperability? Blockchain interoperability is the wide array of methods that allow blockchains to communicate and work more effectively. Most blockchains are not built to be interoperable. No matter how many features a blockchain might have, the transactions are meant to occur within one network. In the simplest terms, interoperability is the freedom to exchange data. One issue that arises when discussing interoperability is trust. If an asset leaves a network, it becomes difficult to trust its validity. Each blockchain has a consensus mechanism that it uses to validate data. True interoperability will entail blockchains being able to understand and process the authenticity of data from different chains. While it may seem obvious that blockchains should be designed to be interoperable, it rarely happens. However, blockchain APIs are working to meet the challenge as the benefits of interoperability become obvious. It is not the first time interoperability challenges have threatened to stifle technology adoption. The World Wide Web today would not have been possible without extensive interoperability solutions. Without various interoperability solutions, people would need hundreds of browsers to open websites and numerous operating systems on one device to use different apps. However, various innovations in interoperability have made it possible for the web to be accessible on just one device. One important solution came in the form of the W3C Consortium. Over the years, it has created common standards enabling various ecosystems to interact and operate in a common language. The semantics created by the W3C have been crucial to speaking a common language on the internet. Due to these common standards, the possibilities of the internet are endless. Blockchain APIs will have a similar role in the mass adoption of blockchain technology. They will enable different ecosystems to communicate and share data, leading to new use cases. Consequently, it will promote mass adoption. The Current State of Blockchain Technology One of the main facts about blockchain today is that no single protocol will become dominant. Instead, blockchain protocols will have to become interoperable. In the enterprise space, a few front runners have emerged: Corda and Hyperledger Fabric. However, in the public blockchain space, things are more fragmented. In short, one blockchain network will not emerge that can meet all the needs of the different use cases possible using the technology. Instead, the industry will comprise many networks, each fulfilling a niche need. One possible outcome is that data from private networks are routed to other networks without achieving one-on-one integration. Blockchain APIs will be crucial in this role. They are needed to move data across blockchains without creating a new market for intermediaries. The Role of Blockchain APIs in Interoperability Interoperability of blockchains can be accomplished by ensuring the smooth transfer of data across different chains. The transfer occurs across APIs, designed to help systems communicate with each other. A Blockchain API is a well-established tool that does not have any specialized blockchain programming knowledge to use. APIs are flexible and expedient. However, they require one-on-one integration between networks, which can be inefficient if incorrectly handled. Additionally, they require some negotiation between platforms. One issue with implementing blockchain APIs is that they do not require cross-platform checks. As such, unauthenticated data can be sent from one blockchain mechanism to another. One way to avoid this is by creating data standards. The standards must be based on a common organizing principle for interoperability at scale. Once such as standard is established, interoperability will speed up. Interoperability Best Practices One of the best solutions to blockchain interoperability would be the creation of common standards and the creation of a network of networks structure. After that, networks could converge around it. In existing industries that aim to adopt the blockchain, creating a neutral working group will establish common standards. Such a model would also need to support cross-chain validation of transactions. In general, the right implementation is crucial to the success of blockchain interoperability. To solve the interoperability challenges, not only technology issues will have to be solved but governance issues as well. Additionally, data ownership and commercial business models will need to be considered. While blockchain APIs offer the technological solution to interoperability, a series of interconnected topics need to be considered. Solving these other issues will help create a holistic approach to the mass adoption of blockchain technology. Summary Interoperability powered by blockchain APIs will improve the productivity of the entire blockchain industry. It will allow users to move assets and data across networks fast, increasing flexibility for the masses. Instead of being tied to one network, smart contracts can run on multiple chains and oracles, which submit real-world data across various platforms. When combined with the inherent benefits of decentralization, interoperability will act as the basis for the widespread adoption of the blockchain.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/blog/2023/12/blog_12_23.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/blog/2023/12/blog_12_23.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Invest In Our Blockchain Api Adventure</title><link href="/blog/invest-in-our-blockchain-api-adventure/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Invest In Our Blockchain Api Adventure" /><published>2023-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/invest-in-our-blockchain-api-adventure</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/invest-in-our-blockchain-api-adventure/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="dive-into-tomorrow-invest-in-our-blockchain-api-adventure">Dive into Tomorrow: Invest in Our Blockchain API Adventure!</h1>

<p>Hey Trailblazer,</p>

<p>Ever pondered the idea of investing in the future? Well, here’s your golden ticket to something revolutionary—our Blockchain API adventure. Fasten your seatbelt because the journey is about to get exhilarating!</p>

<h2 id="why-take-the-plunge-into-investing-with-us">Why Take the Plunge into Investing with Us?</h2>

<p><strong>Tech Marvel:</strong> Envision the coolest tech out there—our Blockchain API is that and more. This isn’t just an investment; it’s a front-row seat to the technology of tomorrow.</p>

<p><strong>Project Extravaganza:</strong> Your investment isn’t merely funding one project; it’s like holding a VIP pass to a carnival of diverse, game-changing ventures. Think DeFi, supply chain wizardry, and beyond.</p>

<p><strong>Investing in Innovation:</strong> We’re not just pushing boundaries; we’re rewriting the rulebook. Your investment isn’t just a number; it’s a stake in our journey to redefine what’s possible.</p>

<h2 id="your-money-your-impact">Your Money, Your Impact:</h2>

<p><strong>Projects That Wow:</strong> Your funds propel the continuous development of mind-blowing features. We’re not talking about minor tweaks; we’re talking about creating things that leave jaws dropping.</p>

<p><strong>Shout It Loud:</strong> Strategic marketing isn’t just about ads; it’s about making noise. Your investment ensures the world knows about the incredible ride you’re a part of.</p>

<p><strong>Team Dream:</strong> Behind every success is a dream team. Your investment helps us attract and retain these rockstars, ensuring we’re always ahead of the game.</p>

<h2 id="ready-to-invest-in-the-coolest-journey">Ready to Invest in the Coolest Journey?</h2>

<p>This isn’t just about investing; it’s about being part of an epic adventure. The future is knocking, and we want you right there with us.</p>

<p><strong>Invest Now and Let’s Embark on the Blockchain Adventure Together!</strong> 🚀💎</p>

<p>Contact us at support@chaingateway.io for more information.</p>

<p>Cheers to investing in the future,</p>

<p>Anthony Lange<br />
CEO of Chaingateway.io</p>]]></content><author><name>Chaingateway</name></author><category term="Blockchain" /><category term="Investing" /><category term="Technology" /><category term="Future" /><category term="Blockchain API" /><category term="Investment" /><category term="Innovation" /><category term="Technology" /><category term="Future" /><category term="Strategic Marketing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dive into Tomorrow: Invest in Our Blockchain API Adventure! Hey Trailblazer, Ever pondered the idea of investing in the future? Well, here’s your golden ticket to something revolutionary—our Blockchain API adventure. Fasten your seatbelt because the journey is about to get exhilarating! Why Take the Plunge into Investing with Us? Tech Marvel: Envision the coolest tech out there—our Blockchain API is that and more. This isn’t just an investment; it’s a front-row seat to the technology of tomorrow. Project Extravaganza: Your investment isn’t merely funding one project; it’s like holding a VIP pass to a carnival of diverse, game-changing ventures. Think DeFi, supply chain wizardry, and beyond. Investing in Innovation: We’re not just pushing boundaries; we’re rewriting the rulebook. Your investment isn’t just a number; it’s a stake in our journey to redefine what’s possible. Your Money, Your Impact: Projects That Wow: Your funds propel the continuous development of mind-blowing features. We’re not talking about minor tweaks; we’re talking about creating things that leave jaws dropping. Shout It Loud: Strategic marketing isn’t just about ads; it’s about making noise. Your investment ensures the world knows about the incredible ride you’re a part of. Team Dream: Behind every success is a dream team. Your investment helps us attract and retain these rockstars, ensuring we’re always ahead of the game. Ready to Invest in the Coolest Journey? This isn’t just about investing; it’s about being part of an epic adventure. The future is knocking, and we want you right there with us. Invest Now and Let’s Embark on the Blockchain Adventure Together! 🚀💎 Contact us at support@chaingateway.io for more information. Cheers to investing in the future, Anthony Lange CEO of Chaingateway.io]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Set Up A Ethereum Node</title><link href="/blog/How-to-Set-Up-an-Ethereum-Node/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Set Up A Ethereum Node" /><published>2023-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/how-to-set-up-a-ethereum-node</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/How-to-Set-Up-an-Ethereum-Node/"><![CDATA[<p>Ethereum nodes are computers that participate in the Ethereum blockchain network to verify, store, and create blocks. To do this, they rely on software called the client that lets users interact with the blockchain via the JSON-RPC API. Users can parse and verify the blockchain while being able to read or write smart contracts.</p>
<h2 id="requirements">Requirements</h2>
<p>Hardware requirements vary by client. However, they are not that high, as the node only needs to remain synced. Before you install a client, please ensure you have the right resources to run it. The minimum requirements are:</p>
<ul>
  <li>CPU with 2+ cores</li>
  <li>8 GB RAM</li>
  <li>2TB SSD</li>
  <li>10+ MBit/s bandwidth</li>
</ul>

<p>Recommended Requirements:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Fast CPU with 4+ cores</li>
  <li>16 GB+ RAM</li>
  <li>Fast SSD with 2+TB</li>
  <li>25+ MBit/s bandwidth</li>
</ul>

<p>All clients support all three main operating systems, which are Linux, MacOS, and Windows.</p>
<h2 id="running-a-node--local-or-cloud">Running a Node – Local or Cloud</h2>
<p>You can run an Ethereum node on a local computer or a cloud server like <a href="https://cryptonodes.io">Cryptonodes.io</a>, Alchemy, Blockdaemon, or QuickNode. However, to ensure censorship resistance, users should run their nodes on local hardware.
Plug and Play
The simplest solution for a local node is a plug-and-play box. These pre-configured machines offer a simple node experience. You buy one, connect it, and run it. The boxes feature an intuitive guide and a dashboard to monitor and control the software. Two options you can try are:</p>
<ul>
  <li>DappNode</li>
  <li>Avado</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="ethereum-on-a-single-board-computer">Ethereum on a Single-Board Computer</h2>
<p>You can run an Ethereum node on a single-board computer, such as an ARM architecture like Raspberry Pi. If you wish to do this, you can find easy-to-run images of multiple execution and consensus clients for Raspberry Pi and other ARM boards on Ethereum on ARM. However, these boards have limited performance.</p>
<h2 id="setting-up-the-node">Setting up the Node</h2>
<p>The client setup can be done via automated launchers or manually by setting up the software yourself. Using a launcher is recommended for less advanced users. For advanced users, the setup guide is easy to follow.</p>
<h2 id="setup-guide">Setup Guide</h2>
<p>Some of the best launchers out there that have automated the client setup process are:</p>
<ul>
  <li>DappNode
It does not come with a machine from the vendor. Instead, the software, node launcher, and control center can be used on any hardware.</li>
  <li>eth-docker
This is an automated setup using Docker for easy and secure staking. Users need a basic terminal and Docker know-how. It is best suited to advanced users.</li>
  <li>Stereum
This is a launcher to install clients on a remote server using an SSH connection with a GUI setup guide, control center, and many more features.</li>
  <li>NiceNode
It is a launcher with a simple user experience to run a node. To use it, pick your client and start it up in a few clicks.</li>
  <li>Sedge
This is an automated node setup tool that will generate a Docker configuration using the CLI wizard and is written in Go by Nethermind.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="manual-clients-setup">Manual Clients Setup</h2>
<p>You have the option to download, verify, and configure the client software yourself. A manual setup offers more versatility. To run the node, you will need to run a pair of consensus and execution clients. Some clients have a light client and sync without requiring any software. However, full trustless verification needs both implementations.</p>
<h3 id="the-client-software">The Client Software</h3>
<p>The first step is to download your preferred execution client and consensus client software. You can download an executable application or an installation package that suits your architecture and OS.
Ensure you verify the signatures and checksums of the packages you download. Some clients come with repositories or Docker images for easy installation and updates. All clients are open-source, which means you can build them from the source. While this is more complex, it may be required. The instructions for each client are provided in the documentation for the client lists link above.
Execution clients</p>
<ul>
  <li>Besu</li>
  <li>Erigon (Does not offer a pre-built binary; it has to be compiled)</li>
  <li>Geth</li>
  <li>Nethermind</li>
</ul>

<p>The client diversity is an issue on the execution layer. Consequently, readers should consider running a minority execution client.
Consensus clients</p>
<ul>
  <li>Lighthouse</li>
  <li>Lodestar (Does not come with a pre-built binary, only a Docker image or build one from source)</li>
  <li>Nimbus</li>
  <li>Prysm</li>
  <li>Teku</li>
</ul>

<p>Client diversity y is crucial for consensus nodes that run validators. If all validators are running a single client implementation, it places the network’s security at risk. It is therefore recommended to pick a minority client.</p>
<h2 id="verifying-software">Verifying Software</h2>
<p>When you download software from the internet, you should verify its integrity. It is one of the potential attack vectors when operating an Ethereum node. When you download a pre-built binary, ensure you trust it and take the risk that an attacker could swap the executable for a malicious program.
Developers will sign their binaries with a PGP key to allow users to cryptographically verify they are running the correct software. To do this, obtain the public key from the developer in the client release pages or the documentation. You can then use a simple PGP implementation such as GnuPG to verify them.
You can also use the hash and cryptographic fingerprint of the software and check that it matches the one given by the developers. It is easier than PGP, and some clients come with just this option. All you need to do is run the hash function on the software and compare it with the one from the release page.</p>
<h2 id="client-setup">Client Setup</h2>
<p>Once you install, download, or compile the client software, you can run it. It means that it has to be executed in the right configuration. There are numerous configuration options offered by clients, which enable various features.
Sync modes are one of the most important features which can affect client performance and data usage. They represent the various methods of downloading and validating blockchain data. You must decide what network and sync mode you will use before starting a node.
The things that you will consider are the disk space and sync time needed. If the default sync mode of the client does not suit your needs, pick another one based on cost, security level, and available data. You also have the option to set up pruning of old data. Pruning removes outdated data, such as state trie nodes, which are unreachable from recent blocks.
Starting The Execution Client
Before you start up the client software, perform a last check to ensure everything is ready. This includes checking disk space, memory, and CPU state, OS is updated, System time and data, and that your router and firewall accept connections on listening ports. To ensure everything is okay, run the client on the testnet first.
Running An Execution Client
Below is an example of a basic configuration to start an execution client.
Running Geth
The example starts Geth on the mainnet, stores data at /data/ethereum, enables JSON RPC, and defines the allowed namespaces. Additionally, it enables authentication for connecting consensus clients, which requires a path to jwtsecret, and the option defining which connections are allowed. In this example, only from localhost.
1 geth –mainnet <br />
2 –datadir “/data/ethereum” <br />
3 –http –authrpc.addr localhost <br />
4 –authrpc.vhosts=”localhost” <br />
5 –authrpc.port 8551
6 –authrpc.jwtsecret=/path/to/jwtsecret</p>

<p>You can learn more about running Geth with a consensus client here.
The execution client will start its core functions, pick endpoints, and begin searching for peers. Once it discovers peers, it will start syncing. The execution client will then wait for a connection from the consensus client. The current blockchain data will be available when the client has synced to the current state.
Starting The Consensus Client
A consensus client has to be started with the correct port configuration to establish a local RPC connection to the execution client. It has to be run with the exposed execution client port as a configuration argument.
It also needs the path to the execution client’s jwt-secret to authenticate the RPC connection between them. Each consensus client has a configuration flag that takes the jwt token file path as an argument. It must be consistent with the jwtsecret path provided to the execution client.
When running a validator node, ensure that you add a configuration flag that specifies the Ethereum address of the fee recipient. The address is where ether rewards are sent.
Running A Consensus Client
An example of a consensus client is Lodestar. To run it, install the Lodestar software by compiling it or download the Docker image. You can find an advanced setup guide here.
1 lodestar beacon <br />
2 –rootDir=”/data/ethereum” <br />
3 –network=mainnet <br />
4 –eth1.enabled=true <br />
5 –execution.urls=”http://127.0.0.1:8551” <br />
6 –jwt-secret=”/path/to/jwtsecret”</p>

<p>When the consensus client connects to the execution client to read the deposit contract and identify validators, it will also connect to other Beacon Node peers. It will then start syncing consensus slots from the genesis block. Once it reaches the current block, the Beacon API will become usable for your validators.</p>
<h2 id="adding-validators">Adding Validators</h2>
<p>The consensus client is the Beacon Node for validators to connect. Each consensus client has its own validator software, which is described in its documentation.
Running a validator allows for sol staking, which is the most impactful and trustless means of supporting Ethereum. However, one has to deposit 32 ETH. To run a validator on your node with a lesser amount, you can use a decentralized pool with permissionless node operators such as Rocket Pool.</p>
<h2 id="operating-a-node">Operating A Node</h2>
<p>You should monitor your node often to ensure it runs correctly. Sometimes, it needs maintenance. While it does not need to be online all the time, it should be online as much as possible to ensure it is synced up to the network.</p>
<h2 id="updating-clients">Updating Clients</h2>
<p>Client software needs to be kept up-to-date to ensure it has all the security patches, features, and EIPs. This is especially important before a hard fork. Before a major network update, a blog is published to inform the community. You can subscribe to these announcements to receive an email when a node needs to be updated.</p>
<h2 id="chaingatewayio-offers-a-simple-solution">Chaingateway.io Offers a Simple Solution</h2>
<p>Setting up and maintaining a node is a lot of work, and very complex. However, you can get direct access to the blockchain without all the hassle via chaingateway.io.</p>
<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>There are different types of Ethereum nodes, which include light nodes, full nodes, and archive nodes. Each has varying requirements. Running a node makes you an important participant in the global decentralized network and contributes to its security and decentralization.</p>]]></content><author><name>Chaingateway</name></author><category term="Blockchain" /><category term="Ethereum" /><category term="Node" /><category term="Web3" /><category term="Blockchain" /><category term="“Blockchain API”" /><category term="Ethereum" /><category term="Smart Contracts" /><category term="Security" /><category term="Web3" /><category term="Ethereum Node" /><category term="Nodes" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ethereum nodes are computers that participate in the Ethereum blockchain network to verify, store, and create blocks. To do this, they rely on software called the client that lets users interact with the blockchain via the JSON-RPC API. Users can parse and verify the blockchain while being able to read or write smart contracts. Requirements Hardware requirements vary by client. However, they are not that high, as the node only needs to remain synced. Before you install a client, please ensure you have the right resources to run it. The minimum requirements are: CPU with 2+ cores 8 GB RAM 2TB SSD 10+ MBit/s bandwidth Recommended Requirements: Fast CPU with 4+ cores 16 GB+ RAM Fast SSD with 2+TB 25+ MBit/s bandwidth All clients support all three main operating systems, which are Linux, MacOS, and Windows. Running a Node – Local or Cloud You can run an Ethereum node on a local computer or a cloud server like Cryptonodes.io, Alchemy, Blockdaemon, or QuickNode. However, to ensure censorship resistance, users should run their nodes on local hardware. Plug and Play The simplest solution for a local node is a plug-and-play box. These pre-configured machines offer a simple node experience. You buy one, connect it, and run it. The boxes feature an intuitive guide and a dashboard to monitor and control the software. Two options you can try are: DappNode Avado Ethereum on a Single-Board Computer You can run an Ethereum node on a single-board computer, such as an ARM architecture like Raspberry Pi. If you wish to do this, you can find easy-to-run images of multiple execution and consensus clients for Raspberry Pi and other ARM boards on Ethereum on ARM. However, these boards have limited performance. Setting up the Node The client setup can be done via automated launchers or manually by setting up the software yourself. Using a launcher is recommended for less advanced users. For advanced users, the setup guide is easy to follow. Setup Guide Some of the best launchers out there that have automated the client setup process are: DappNode It does not come with a machine from the vendor. Instead, the software, node launcher, and control center can be used on any hardware. eth-docker This is an automated setup using Docker for easy and secure staking. Users need a basic terminal and Docker know-how. It is best suited to advanced users. Stereum This is a launcher to install clients on a remote server using an SSH connection with a GUI setup guide, control center, and many more features. NiceNode It is a launcher with a simple user experience to run a node. To use it, pick your client and start it up in a few clicks. Sedge This is an automated node setup tool that will generate a Docker configuration using the CLI wizard and is written in Go by Nethermind. Manual Clients Setup You have the option to download, verify, and configure the client software yourself. A manual setup offers more versatility. To run the node, you will need to run a pair of consensus and execution clients. Some clients have a light client and sync without requiring any software. However, full trustless verification needs both implementations. The Client Software The first step is to download your preferred execution client and consensus client software. You can download an executable application or an installation package that suits your architecture and OS. Ensure you verify the signatures and checksums of the packages you download. Some clients come with repositories or Docker images for easy installation and updates. All clients are open-source, which means you can build them from the source. While this is more complex, it may be required. The instructions for each client are provided in the documentation for the client lists link above. Execution clients Besu Erigon (Does not offer a pre-built binary; it has to be compiled) Geth Nethermind The client diversity is an issue on the execution layer. Consequently, readers should consider running a minority execution client. Consensus clients Lighthouse Lodestar (Does not come with a pre-built binary, only a Docker image or build one from source) Nimbus Prysm Teku Client diversity y is crucial for consensus nodes that run validators. If all validators are running a single client implementation, it places the network’s security at risk. It is therefore recommended to pick a minority client. Verifying Software When you download software from the internet, you should verify its integrity. It is one of the potential attack vectors when operating an Ethereum node. When you download a pre-built binary, ensure you trust it and take the risk that an attacker could swap the executable for a malicious program. Developers will sign their binaries with a PGP key to allow users to cryptographically verify they are running the correct software. To do this, obtain the public key from the developer in the client release pages or the documentation. You can then use a simple PGP implementation such as GnuPG to verify them. You can also use the hash and cryptographic fingerprint of the software and check that it matches the one given by the developers. It is easier than PGP, and some clients come with just this option. All you need to do is run the hash function on the software and compare it with the one from the release page. Client Setup Once you install, download, or compile the client software, you can run it. It means that it has to be executed in the right configuration. There are numerous configuration options offered by clients, which enable various features. Sync modes are one of the most important features which can affect client performance and data usage. They represent the various methods of downloading and validating blockchain data. You must decide what network and sync mode you will use before starting a node. The things that you will consider are the disk space and sync time needed. If the default sync mode of the client does not suit your needs, pick another one based on cost, security level, and available data. You also have the option to set up pruning of old data. Pruning removes outdated data, such as state trie nodes, which are unreachable from recent blocks. Starting The Execution Client Before you start up the client software, perform a last check to ensure everything is ready. This includes checking disk space, memory, and CPU state, OS is updated, System time and data, and that your router and firewall accept connections on listening ports. To ensure everything is okay, run the client on the testnet first. Running An Execution Client Below is an example of a basic configuration to start an execution client. Running Geth The example starts Geth on the mainnet, stores data at /data/ethereum, enables JSON RPC, and defines the allowed namespaces. Additionally, it enables authentication for connecting consensus clients, which requires a path to jwtsecret, and the option defining which connections are allowed. In this example, only from localhost. 1 geth –mainnet 2 –datadir “/data/ethereum” 3 –http –authrpc.addr localhost 4 –authrpc.vhosts=”localhost” 5 –authrpc.port 8551 6 –authrpc.jwtsecret=/path/to/jwtsecret You can learn more about running Geth with a consensus client here. The execution client will start its core functions, pick endpoints, and begin searching for peers. Once it discovers peers, it will start syncing. The execution client will then wait for a connection from the consensus client. The current blockchain data will be available when the client has synced to the current state. Starting The Consensus Client A consensus client has to be started with the correct port configuration to establish a local RPC connection to the execution client. It has to be run with the exposed execution client port as a configuration argument. It also needs the path to the execution client’s jwt-secret to authenticate the RPC connection between them. Each consensus client has a configuration flag that takes the jwt token file path as an argument. It must be consistent with the jwtsecret path provided to the execution client. When running a validator node, ensure that you add a configuration flag that specifies the Ethereum address of the fee recipient. The address is where ether rewards are sent. Running A Consensus Client An example of a consensus client is Lodestar. To run it, install the Lodestar software by compiling it or download the Docker image. You can find an advanced setup guide here. 1 lodestar beacon 2 –rootDir=”/data/ethereum” 3 –network=mainnet 4 –eth1.enabled=true 5 –execution.urls=”http://127.0.0.1:8551” 6 –jwt-secret=”/path/to/jwtsecret” When the consensus client connects to the execution client to read the deposit contract and identify validators, it will also connect to other Beacon Node peers. It will then start syncing consensus slots from the genesis block. Once it reaches the current block, the Beacon API will become usable for your validators. Adding Validators The consensus client is the Beacon Node for validators to connect. Each consensus client has its own validator software, which is described in its documentation. Running a validator allows for sol staking, which is the most impactful and trustless means of supporting Ethereum. However, one has to deposit 32 ETH. To run a validator on your node with a lesser amount, you can use a decentralized pool with permissionless node operators such as Rocket Pool. Operating A Node You should monitor your node often to ensure it runs correctly. Sometimes, it needs maintenance. While it does not need to be online all the time, it should be online as much as possible to ensure it is synced up to the network. Updating Clients Client software needs to be kept up-to-date to ensure it has all the security patches, features, and EIPs. This is especially important before a hard fork. Before a major network update, a blog is published to inform the community. You can subscribe to these announcements to receive an email when a node needs to be updated. Chaingateway.io Offers a Simple Solution Setting up and maintaining a node is a lot of work, and very complex. However, you can get direct access to the blockchain without all the hassle via chaingateway.io. Summary There are different types of Ethereum nodes, which include light nodes, full nodes, and archive nodes. Each has varying requirements. Running a node makes you an important participant in the global decentralized network and contributes to its security and decentralization.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/blog/2023/11/blog_11_10.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/blog/2023/11/blog_11_10.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Set Up A Tron Node</title><link href="/blog/How-to-Set-Up-a-Tron-Node/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Set Up A Tron Node" /><published>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/how-to-set-up-a-tron-node</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/How-to-Set-Up-a-Tron-Node/"><![CDATA[<p>Tron is a blockchain platform working on creating a decentralized global digital content entertainment system. The Tron network relies on nodes spread throughout the world to validate transactions and maintain the security of the network. Here are the steps to set up a Tron Node.</p>
<h2 id="requirements">Requirements</h2>
<ul>
  <li>The Tron Node can be set up on Linux or MacOS.</li>
  <li>The recommended configuration is:</li>
  <li>Recommended Configuration</li>
  <li>CPU：16 cores</li>
  <li>RAM：32G</li>
  <li>SSD：2.5T+</li>
  <li>Bandwidth：100M</li>
  <li>the recommended configuration for creating a full node for block production is as follows:</li>
  <li>CPU：32 cores</li>
  <li>RAM：64G</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="deployment-steps">Deployment Steps</h2>
<p>No matter the type of node, the deployment process is the same:</p>
<h3 id="step-1---install-tools-and-dependencies">Step 1 - Install Tools and Dependencies</h3>
<p>You will require Oracle JDK 1.8 and git</p>
<h3 id="step-2--download-the-tron-full-node">Step 2 – Download the Tron Full Node</h3>
<p>The next step is to download the full node. You can obtain the FullNode.jar by compiling the source code or by downloading <a href="https://github.com/tronprotocol/java-tron/releases">the released jar</a> directly.</p>
<h3 id="step-3--start-the-node">Step 3 – Start the Node</h3>
<p>In this step, you must first get the mainnet configure file: <a href="https://github.com/tronprotocol/tron-deployment/blob/master/main_net_config.conf">main_net_config.conf</a>. You can find other network configuration files <a href="https://github.com/tronprotocol/tron-deployment">here</a>.
The full node contains the full historical data and acts as the entry point into the Tron Network. It provides HTTP APIL and Grpc API for external query. Using the fullnode, you can interact with the Tron Network. For instance, you can deploy contracts, interact with contracts, transfer assets, and more.
The startup command for the mainnet fullnode is detailed below. The -c parameter specifies the configuration file of the fullnode.</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$ java -Xmx24g -XX:+UseConcMarkSweepGC -jar FullNode.jar -c main_net_config.conf</code></p>

<p>-XX:+UseConcMarkSweepGC ：Specifies parallel garbage collection. To be placed before the -jar parameter, not at the end.
-Xmx ：The maximum value of the JVM heap, which can be set to 80% of the physical memory.
To start up a fullnode that can produce blocks for the mainnet, you should add the –witness parameter to the startup command; fullnode will run as a node that produces blocks. Besides supporting all functions of fullnode, the block-producing fullnode also supports block production and transaction packaging.
Ensure you have a super representative account and receive votes from others. If the votes rank in the top 27, you will have to start a fullnode that can produce blocks to begin block production.
You will also need to fill in the private key of the super representative address into the localwitness list in the main_net_config.conf. Alternatively, you can use the keystore + password method if you do not want to specify the private key in plain text. Here is how to do it. Once you do that, run this command to start the node:</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">$ java -Xmx24g -XX:+UseConcMarkSweepGC -jar FullNode.jar --witness -c main_net_config.conf</code></p>

<p>Due to the size of the mainnet and nile testnet, it will take some time for the data to be synchronized. You can use <a href="https://developers.tron.network/docs/main-net-database-snapshots">Data Snapshots</a> to speed up the process. To do this, you will need to download the latest data snapshot and extract it to the output-directory directory of the Tron project. You can then start the node that it synchronizes using the data snapshot.
To shut down the fullnode, you can use the command <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kill -15 process id</code>.</p>
<h3 id="step-4--verify-the-full-node">Step 4- Verify the Full Node</h3>
<p>Once a node is synced, you can verify its status using the Tron Grid API. Run this command in a new terminal window:
tron-grid status
It will return information about the node, including the block height and the version of the software. Once that is done, you are now a successful operator of a Tron Network full node.</p>
<h2 id="try-chaingatewayio">Try Chaingateway.io</h2>
<p>Setting up and maintaining a Tron Network node can be a lot of work. It is complex, and difficult to master. However, <a href="https://chaingateway.io">Chaingateway.io</a> has the perfect solution. The platform offers direct access to the Tron blockchain without all the complexity.</p>
<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>Running a full node requires huge resources, including storage space and bandwidth. You also have to keep the node updated with the latest software releases to ensure it works properly and is secure. Running a node is crucial for developers who want to build on Tron or take part in the consensus mechanism. Using the steps above, you should be well on your way to setting up a full node and interaction with the Blockchain.</p>]]></content><author><name>Chaingateway</name></author><category term="Blockchain" /><category term="Tron" /><category term="API" /><category term="Tron Node" /><category term="Web3" /><category term="Blockchain APIs" /><category term="Blockchain Nodes" /><category term="Tron Network" /><category term="Security" /><category term="Web3" /><category term="Tron Node" /><category term="Tron Blockchain" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to set up a Tron Network node to help authenticate transactions on the Tron Blockchain Network.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/blog/2023/10/blog_10_16.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/blog/2023/10/blog_10_16.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Set Up A Binance Smart Chain Node</title><link href="/blog/How-to-Set-Up-a-Binance-Smart-Chain-Node/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Set Up A Binance Smart Chain Node" /><published>2023-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/how-to-set-up-a-binance-smart-chain-node</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/How-to-Set-Up-a-Binance-Smart-Chain-Node/"><![CDATA[<p>BNB Smart or BSC is a blockchain working to provide an alternative and extension to the Ethereum blockchain. It achieves this via several innovative implementations made during the creation of the platform. This is a guide on how to set up a BSC node.</p>
<h2 id="requirements">Requirements</h2>
<ul>
  <li>VPS running recent versions of Mac OS X or Linux</li>
  <li>3TB of free disk space, solid-state drive(SSD), gp3, 8k IOPS, 250MB/S throughput, read latency &lt;1ms. (if starting with snap sync, it requires NVMe SSD.)</li>
  <li>16 cores of CPU and 64 gigabytes of RAM</li>
  <li>Suggest m5zn.3xlarge instance type on AWS, c2-standard-16 on Google cloud</li>
  <li>A broadband Internet connection with upload/download speeds of 5 megabytes per second</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="deployment-steps">Deployment Steps</h2>
<p>Whether you are running a Validator Node or a Witness Node, the process is similar. The recommended method is to sync from a snapshot.</p>
<h3 id="step-1---download-the-pre-build-binaries">Step 1 - Download the Pre-Build Binaries</h3>
<p>These can be accessed from the <a href="https://github.com/bnb-chain/bsc/releases/latest">release page</a>.</p>
<h3 id="step-2---download-the-config-files">Step 2 - Download The Config Files</h3>
<p>Download genesis.json and config.toml by doing the following:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">wget <span class="si">$(</span>curl <span class="nt">-s</span> https://api.github.com/repos/bnb-chain/bsc/releases/latest |grep browser_ |grep mainnet |cut <span class="nt">-d</span><span class="se">\"</span> <span class="nt">-f4</span><span class="si">)</span>

unzip mainnet.zip</code></pre></figure>

<h3 id="step-3---download-snapshot">Step 3 - Download Snapshot</h3>
<p>You can find the latest chain data snapshot <a href="https://github.com/bnb-chain/bsc-snapshots">here</a>. Follow the guide to structure your files.
The –datadir flag should point to the folder where the extracted snapshot data is. For instance, you can create a folder named node and move the extracted snapshot data to the folder.</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell"><span class="nb">mv </span>server/data-seed/geth/chaindata node/geth/chaindata

<span class="nb">mv </span>server/data-seed/geth/chaindata node/geth/triecache</code></pre></figure>

<h3 id="step-4---start-a-full-node">Step 4 - Start a Full Node</h3>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">./geth <span class="nt">--config</span> ./config.toml <span class="nt">--datadir</span> ./node <span class="nt">--cache</span> 8000 <span class="nt">--rpc</span>.allow-unprotected-txs <span class="nt">--txlookuplimit</span> 0</code></pre></figure>

<p>Ensure that you use the version of geth download with wget above and not the local installation of geth, which could be the wrong version.
The recommended setup entails running a fast node, which is a full node with the flag –tries-verify-mode none to ensure high performance if you do not care about state consistency. You can find the details on running a fast node <a href="https://docs.bnbchain.org/docs/BSC-fast-node">here</a>.</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">./geth <span class="nt">--config</span> ./config.toml <span class="nt">--datadir</span> ./node <span class="nt">--cache</span> 8000 <span class="nt">--rpc</span>.allow-unprotected-txs <span class="nt">--txlookuplimit</span> 0 <span class="nt">--tries-verify-mode</span> none</code></pre></figure>

<h3 id="step-5--verify-the-node-status">Step 5 -Verify the Node Status</h3>
<p>By default, you can monitor the log from ./node/bsc.log. When the node begins syncing, you will see this output:
You can monitor the log from ./node/bsc.log by default. When your node starts syncing, you should be able to see the following output:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell"><span class="nv">t</span><span class="o">=</span>2022-09-08T13:00:27+0000 <span class="nv">lvl</span><span class="o">=</span>info <span class="nv">msg</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">"Imported new chain segment"</span>            
<span class="nv">blocks</span><span class="o">=</span>1 <span class="nv">txs</span><span class="o">=</span>177 <span class="nv">mgas</span><span class="o">=</span>17.317  
<span class="nv">elapsed</span><span class="o">=</span>31.131ms   
<span class="nv">mgasps</span><span class="o">=</span>556.259 <span class="nv">number</span><span class="o">=</span>21,153,429 <span class="nb">hash</span><span class="o">=</span>0x42e6b54ba7106387f0650defc62c9ace3160b427702dab7bd1c5abb83a32d8db <span class="nv">dirty</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">"0.00 B"</span>
<span class="nv">t</span><span class="o">=</span>2022-09-08T13:00:29+0000 <span class="nv">lvl</span><span class="o">=</span>info <span class="nv">msg</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">"Imported new chain segment"</span>            
<span class="nv">blocks</span><span class="o">=</span>1 <span class="nv">txs</span><span class="o">=</span>251 <span class="nv">mgas</span><span class="o">=</span>39.638  
<span class="nv">elapsed</span><span class="o">=</span>68.827ms   
<span class="nv">mgasps</span><span class="o">=</span>575.900 <span class="nv">number</span><span class="o">=</span>21,153,430 <span class="nb">hash</span><span class="o">=</span>0xa3397b273b31b013e43487689782f20c03f47525b4cd4107c1715af45a88796e <span class="nv">dirty</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">"0.00 B"</span>
<span class="nv">t</span><span class="o">=</span>2022-09-08T13:00:33+0000 <span class="nv">lvl</span><span class="o">=</span>info <span class="nv">msg</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">"Imported new chain segment"</span>            
<span class="nv">blocks</span><span class="o">=</span>1 <span class="nv">txs</span><span class="o">=</span>197 <span class="nv">mgas</span><span class="o">=</span>19.364  
<span class="nv">elapsed</span><span class="o">=</span>34.663ms   
<span class="nv">mgasps</span><span class="o">=</span>558.632 <span class="nv">number</span><span class="o">=</span>21,153,431 <span class="nb">hash</span><span class="o">=</span>0x0c7872b698f28cb5c36a8a3e1e315b1d31bda6109b15467a9735a12380e2ad14 <span class="nv">dirty</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">"0.00 B"</span></code></pre></figure>

<h2 id="syncing-from-the-genesis-block">Syncing From the Genesis Block</h2>
<p>This is not recommended as it requires more powerful resources. The server should have an IOPS of at least 40k and be at least an i3/i3en series server.</p>
<h3 id="step-1---write-the-genesis-state-locally">Step 1 - Write the Genesis State Locally</h3>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">./geth <span class="nt">--datadir</span> node init genesis.json</code></pre></figure>

<p>Once done, you will see this output:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">INFO <span class="o">[</span>05-19|14:53:17.468] Allocated cache and file handles        
<span class="nv">database</span><span class="o">=</span>/Users/huangsuyu/Downloads/bsc/node/geth/chaindata <span class="nv">cache</span><span class="o">=</span>16.00MiB <span class="nv">handles</span><span class="o">=</span>16
INFO <span class="o">[</span>05-19|14:53:17.498] Writing custom genesis block
INFO <span class="o">[</span>05-19|14:53:17.501] Persisted trie from memory database <span class="nv">nodes</span><span class="o">=</span>21 <span class="nv">size</span><span class="o">=</span>56.84KiB <span class="nb">time</span><span class="o">=</span>357.915µs <span class="nv">gcnodes</span><span class="o">=</span>0 <span class="nv">gcsize</span><span class="o">=</span>0.00B <span class="nv">gctime</span><span class="o">=</span>0s <span class="nv">livenodes</span><span class="o">=</span>1 <span class="nv">livesize</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nt">-574</span>.00B
INFO <span class="o">[</span>05-19|14:53:17.502] Successfully wrote genesis state <span class="nv">database</span><span class="o">=</span>chaindata <span class="nb">hash</span><span class="o">=</span>7d79cc…fb0d1e
INFO <span class="o">[</span>05-19|14:53:17.503] Allocated cache and file handles        
<span class="nv">database</span><span class="o">=</span>/Users/huangsuyu/Downloads/bsc/node/geth/lightchaindata <span class="nv">cache</span><span class="o">=</span>16.00MiB <span class="nv">handles</span><span class="o">=</span>16
INFO <span class="o">[</span>05-19|14:53:17.524] Writing custom genesis block
INFO <span class="o">[</span>05-19|14:53:17.525] Persisted trie from memory database <span class="nv">nodes</span><span class="o">=</span>21 <span class="nv">size</span><span class="o">=</span>56.84KiB <span class="nb">time</span><span class="o">=</span>638.396µs <span class="nv">gcnodes</span><span class="o">=</span>0 <span class="nv">gcsize</span><span class="o">=</span>0.00B <span class="nv">gctime</span><span class="o">=</span>0s <span class="nv">livenodes</span><span class="o">=</span>1 <span class="nv">livesize</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nt">-574</span>.00B
INFO <span class="o">[</span>05-19|14:53:17.528] Successfully wrote genesis state <span class="nv">database</span><span class="o">=</span>lightchaindata <span class="nb">hash</span><span class="o">=</span>7d79cc…fb0d1e</code></pre></figure>

<h3 id="step-2---start-fullnode">Step 2 - Start Fullnode</h3>
<h2 id="start-a-full-node">Start a Full Node</h2>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">./geth <span class="nt">--config</span> ./config.toml <span class="nt">--datadir</span> ./node <span class="nt">--cache</span> 8000 <span class="nt">--rpc</span>.allow-unprotected-txs <span class="nt">--txlookuplimit</span> 0</code></pre></figure>

<h2 id="types-of-sync-mode">Types of Sync Mode</h2>
<p>When running a full node, there are two sync modes. These are snap and full, which be verified by flag –syncmode.
The snap mode is used for the initial sync. It downloads the latest state instead of executing blocks from the Genesis block. When the initial sync is over, it switches to full sync.
A full sync can also be used for the initial sync, which will execute all blocks from the genesis block. However, the amount of historical data is high, and it is thus not recommended. Instead, download a snapshot from the <a href="https://github.com/bnb-chain/bsc-snapshots">official repo</a> and begin the full sync using the snapshot.
If you do not provide the flag syncmode, the default sync mode will depend on the state of the data folder. It will be a snap mode if you sync from the genesis or full mode if you start from a snapshot.</p>
<h2 id="local-private-network">Local Private Network</h2>
<p>To set up a local private network, refer to the <a href="https://github.com/bnb-chain/node-deploy">BSC-Deploy Tools</a>.</p>
<h2 id="node-maintenance">Node Maintenance</h2>
<p>Read <a href="https://docs.bnbchain.org/docs/validator/node-maintenance">this guide</a> for node maintenance.</p>
<h2 id="upgrade-geth">Upgrade Geth</h2>
<p>Read <a href="https://docs.bnbchain.org/docs/upgrade-fullnode">this guide</a> on how to upgrade geth.</p>
<h2 id="try-chaingatewayio">Try Chaingateway.io</h2>
<p>Before you get started, you should know that setting up and maintaining a BSC Network node is a complex, and difficult task. Luckily, <a href="https://chaingateway.io">chaingateway.io</a> offers the perfect solution. The platform offers direct access to the blockchain, helping you skip all the hassle.</p>
<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>If you follow the steps above, you can now connect to other peers to sync your node. Depending on your region, it may be easier or harder to find peers to share data to sync your chain. The process requires patience. Eventually, you will succeed. With the full node running, you can now send transactions to the blockchain for confirmation without relying on others since you can route your traffic to the node you are operating.</p>]]></content><author><name>Chaingateway</name></author><category term="Blockchain" /><category term="Tutorial" /><category term="Blockchain Nodes" /><category term="Binance Network" /><category term="BSC Network" /><category term="Security" /><category term="Binance Smart Chain" /><category term="“Blockchain APIs”" /><category term="Binance Node" /><category term="Tutorial" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to set up a Binance Smart Chain network node to authenticate transactions on the BSC network.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/blog/2023/10/blog_10_04.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/blog/2023/10/blog_10_04.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Use Cases Of A Blockchain Api</title><link href="/blog/Use-Cases-of-a-Blockchain-API/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Use Cases Of A Blockchain Api" /><published>2023-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/use-cases-of-a-blockchain-api</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Use-Cases-of-a-Blockchain-API/"><![CDATA[<p>As blockchain technology continues to evolve, developers are racing to keep up with potential use cases. Mastering blockchain APIs will be crucial to successfully implementing these use cases.</p>
<h2 id="understanding-blockchain-api-technology">Understanding Blockchain API Technology</h2>
<p>A blockchain API is a tool used to help developers interact with a blockchain network. It makes it easy to integrate the blockchain into an application or website. In short, it simplifies a developer’s interaction with a blockchain network while assisting them in building a decentralized application. One way it does this is by providing access to data on blocks, smart contracts, transactions, account balances, and more. It lets users send messages on the blockchain without writing their own code.
For developers, they will often interact with APIs using the JSON-RPC architecture. They call on the API via WbSockets or HTTPS to send or receive data from the blockchain. Additionally, they can use standard SDKs to exchange data with a blockchain. There are also enhanced APIs that can save time on the development effort. They include NFT APIs, DeFi APIs, and wallet APIs built on top of a standard API.</p>
<h2 id="use-cases-for-a-blockchain-api">Use Cases for a Blockchain API</h2>
<p>There are numerous use cases for blockchain APIs. They can be used to create DApps, secure data, and power financial technology solutions. Additionally, they can be used to facilitate digital identity authentication.
Blockchain APIs can also build interfaces between blockchain networks and other systems without creating custom code. Additionally, they can access data such as accounts, smart contracts, transaction data, and more.
A specific use case for blockchain APIs is in crypto wallets. A crypto wallet is used to help manage the crypto in your crypto address. The wallet is a central location to manage crypto and connect to DApps. A crypto wallet API can link to different blockchain networks and perform various functions like sales, order placements, and open order cancellations. One example of this is the Binance API.
Another use case is digital banks. A blockchain API allows a bank to integrate its products with crypto banking services like lending, making payments, and accepting deposits. The API can also allow a bank to notify customers about fees and balances.
Blockchain APIs can be used for portfolio tracking. They can feed historical and live blockchain data to portfolio management software, allowing users to manage their crypto assets more efficiently. Such an API can offer a portfolio owner data like transactions made from a given address, track fees, monitor deposits and withdrawals, and more.
APIs are also connected to exchanges to provide various services. For instance, they can sort coins by market cap, daily trading volume, and other metrics. Additionally, they can be used for order placement.
Blockchain APIs are also used for crypto custody services. They allow custody providers to provide users with a digital management solution integrated with a crypto wallet to store crypto securely. These custody services are especially important in storing private keys.
Blockchain APIs can also be connected with crypto mining software to boost efficiency. They track information on the blockchain and notify users when it is most efficient to mine a given network. The result is that miners can maximize their profitability.
Blockchain APIs are also useful for crypto lending services. They are used to give information that can be used to establish a borrower’s credit score. Blockchain APIs are often used to lend and borrow crypto directly between users and to collect interest.
A blockchain API is also useful for crypto accounting and taxes. It ensures that users can accurately calculate how much tax they owe to the last decimal. They work by linking a crypto wallet to a crypto tax app, allowing users to receive real-time updates on their gains and losses. Consequently, they can be used to determine the most advantageous accounting methods for tax purposes.
Blockchain APIs are also useful for facilitating the operation of crypto payment service providers. They can convert crypto via exchange, generate deposit addresses, and more.
A blockchain API is also useful when building a blockchain explorer. An explorer is used to explore data on the blockchain, which is gathered via an API. The API will be useful in ensuring that the explorer presents use and real-time data on the state of the blockchain.
Blockchain APIs are also useful in connecting data from the real world to oracles, which are then sent to smart contracts. Consequently, they allow smart contracts to communicate with the outside world.</p>
<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>As the internet evolves into Web3, crypto, and NFTs will continue to grow. Blockchain APIs will have an important role in facilitating this evolution. They will improve connectivity and create a unified environment for developing various use cases. It will lead to more opportunities for collaboration and ownership. However, the technology still needs fine-tuning, which is already happening. A strong community of developers is emerging to solve the existing challenges. As blockchain APIs speed up blockchain adoption, it will bolster the global economy, making it more efficient and less risky.</p>]]></content><author><name>Chaingateway</name></author><category term="Blockchain" /><category term="API" /><category term="Web3" /><category term="Blockchain APIs" /><category term="DApps" /><category term="Smart Contracts" /><category term="Security" /><category term="Web3" /><category term="Web3 Future" /><category term="Decentralized Web3" /><category term="Use Cases" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A list of the various use cases for a blockchain API to foster efficiency, improve speed of blockchain-based transactions while promoting mass adoption of blockhain technology.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/blog/2023/09/blog_09_14.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/blog/2023/09/blog_09_14.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Use Of Webhooks To Process Deposits Automatically</title><link href="/blog/The-Use-of-Webhooks-to-Process-Deposits-Automatically/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Use Of Webhooks To Process Deposits Automatically" /><published>2023-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/The-Use-of-Webhooks-to-Process-Deposits-Automatically</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/The-Use-of-Webhooks-to-Process-Deposits-Automatically/"><![CDATA[<p>As an app developer, you may have encountered webhook integrations in some of your applications and wondered what they were.
Webhooks are growing in popularity, and you should understand them. According to Google trends, interest in webhooks has risen astronomically in recent years.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-a-webhook">What is a Webhook?</h2>
<p>Webhooks are one of the ways web applications exchange data. They allow real-time data transmission across apps based on a predefined event. For instance, on a restaurant-based app, a webhook would notify you when someone checks in. You can then run any automated processes once the event is triggered. Data will be sent over the web from the app where the event originated to a handling application that receives the signal.
The data exchange happens over a webhook URL created by the receiving app and acts like a phone number that other apps can dial when an event occurs. Data sent to the webhook URL is known as the payload.</p>
<h2 id="the-significance-of-webhooks-in-automating-payments">The Significance of Webhooks in Automating Payments</h2>
<p>For a membership-based site, a webhook would prove useful. Whenever the customer uses the payment gateway to pay for a service, you would have to input their details in the membership app so that they can log in. One way to get over this is to have the payment gateway and your app communication. Consequently, they are automatically added to the membership app when they pay. A webhook is one way to ensure that communication takes place.
Webhooks can save a lot of time, and they are so popular that you can integrate them into most of the web apps you already use. For instance, they can be connected to email marketing software with other apps to create new opportunities.
The webhook could be connected to the payment gateway and the email marketing software so that you receive an alert when a payment bounces. Webhooks can be used to sync customer data in other apps. For instance, when a user changes their email address, the change can be reflected in the CRM. Webhooks are also useful for sending information about events to external databases like Google Big Query for more analysis.
Webhooks can also be used to automate payments. By connecting to the payment gateway, they can send a signal for when an event occurs, which can be used to send the required funds automatically. In the future Web3 internet, webhooks will have a unique role to play in facilitating micropayments and instant settlement. Their ability to instantly send information will be useful for automating payments in Web3.</p>
<h2 id="are-webhooks-apis">Are Webhooks APIs?</h2>
<p>Webhooks and APIs are often mentioned together. However, while they are similar, they are not the same. Webhooks are one of the options that apps can use to exchange data, while API is another option. One of the major differences is in how they receive data.
An API provides data via polling when the app occasionally sends requests for data to an API server to see if it has been updated with new information. A webhook allows the provider to push data to the application as soon as an event is triggered. Consequently, webhooks are sometimes called reverse APIs.
With an API, the application has to pull data from the server to remain updated periodically. At the same time, the webhook receives data pushed from the server when an event is triggered. In the real world, an API is analogous to making periodic calls to a store to ask if they have brought new merchandise. On the other hand, a webhook is a system that lets the retailer call you when they have new merchandise. The result is that it saves time for both parties. Webhooks consume fewer resources since they do not require constant polling for new data.
However, APIs are still popular since not all applications have webhooks integration. Additionally, they do not work for every use case. Sometimes, an app only wants to get information about the end-result instead of every event.
A webhook would only notify the app about an event, while if you need to make changes based on new data, you will still need an API. Another reason APIs are still useful is that the webhook payload may not have all the data you need about the event. To overcome this issue, many applications today support webhooks and APIs.
When webhook integration is lacking, some middleware applications have come in to fill the gap. These apps will poll the API and send the updates using webhooks. Middleware apps with this capability can connect apps that lack webhook integration, allowing them to share data.</p>
<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>Webhooks are an important part of the internet, and their popularity is growing. They allow applications to send data instantly, which is useful for automated payments. While they work similarly to APIs, they have different roles, each with unique use cases. One of the best ways to understand the full capabilities of webhooks is to try them yourself. With a few connections between your apps, you will get a feel for how they work. Within a short time, you will be a pro at using webhooks for everything, including automated payments.</p>]]></content><author><name>Chaingateway</name></author><category term="Blockchain" /><category term="API" /><category term="Web3" /><category term="Blockchain APIs" /><category term="DApps" /><category term="Smart Contracts" /><category term="Security" /><category term="Web3" /><category term="Web3 Future" /><category term="Decentralized Web3" /><category term="Webhooks" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How webhooks can be used to process deposits on the blockchain automatically to improve efficiency, and speed.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/blog/2023/08/bitblade_illustration_of_blockchain_colors_like_image_style_lik_2.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/blog/2023/08/bitblade_illustration_of_blockchain_colors_like_image_style_lik_2.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Blockchain Apis Can Maximize Blockchain Potential</title><link href="/blog/blockchain-apis-can-maximize-blockchain-potential/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blockchain Apis Can Maximize Blockchain Potential" /><published>2023-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/blockchain-apis-can-maximize-blockchain-potential</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/blockchain-apis-can-maximize-blockchain-potential/"><![CDATA[<p>Blockchain technology has greatly impacted how digital asset ownership works, including the transparency of transactions. Blockchain APIs can maximize the potential of the technology.
The Binance Smart Chain (BSC) is one of the most popular blockchain networks, which empowers developers to create new use cases with a comprehensive suite of tools. One of the most powerful tools available to developers is the Binance Smart Chain API. It makes it easy for developers to interact with the blockchain network seamlessly. A blockchain API allows developers to get the most out of the existing capabilities of a blockchain network.</p>
<h2 id="features-of-the-binance-smart-chain-api">Features of the Binance Smart Chain API</h2>
<p>One important feature of the BSC API is a simple and easy-to-use interface that makes it easy for developers to interact with the BSC. It supports multiple programming languages, allowing developers to interact with it in a language they know. The API documentation is also well-structured, providing clear guidelines on effectively using its functions.
Another benefit of the API is that it is a high-performance and scalable API, qualities it inherits from the Binance Smart Chain. Developers will thus have a fast and efficient way to interact with the network. Therefore, Applications built on BSC can handle huge transactions without a drop in performance.
The BSC API is also renowned for being reliable and secure when connecting to the BSC network. It uses industry-leading encryption and authentication to ensure data is safe during transactions. Developers are assured that the API is good for creating secure apps that protect their users’ data.</p>
<h2 id="benefits-of-using-the-bsc-api">Benefits of Using the BSC API</h2>
<p>One of the benefits of using this API is that developers get seamless integration with the BSC ecosystem. They can access numerous resources and tools created by Binance. For instance, they are assured of seamless integration with various DeFi platforms. Developers will have access to a wide array of tools and resources, including the Binance Chain Wallet, Binance, Bridge, and numerous DeFi platforms. The result is that the development process leads to a feature-rich application that leverages the full capabilities of the BSC network.
Another benefit is that it is cost-effective. The BSC network is renowned for its low transaction fees, which makes it a great choice for developers with a small budget. The result is that they can allocate more resources to building their project, like user acquisition and marketing.
Using the BSC API also comes with the added benefit of a large active developer community. The community is always ready to share their wealth of expertise and knowledge. Once they encounter any issue, they can quickly resolve it with guidance on best practices.
Community support is essential to the success of any blockchain project, and developers using the Binance Smart Chain API will benefit from the BSC ecosystem’s large community. It is a vibrant community of developers, enthusiasts, and users. They work together to provide resources and support to BSC API users. A major benefit of the BSC community is its wealth of experience and knowledge.</p>
<h2 id="use-cases-for-the-bsc-api">Use Cases for the BSC API</h2>
<p>The most common use case for the BSC API is in DeFi platforms. BSC network is popular with projects due to its high performance, low transaction fee, and compatibility with the Ethereum network. Developers can create a wide array of DeFi applications on the BSC network, including DEXs yield farming protocols and lending platforms.
Another common use case for the BSC API is the creation of NFT marketplaces. As NFTs have grown in popularity, BSC has emerged as the go-to platform for launching NFT marketplaces. The BSC API allows developers to create an NFT platform that enables trading, creation, and management of NFTs. Using the API, developers can create feature-rich marketplaces that meet the growing demand for NFTs.
The BSC API is also popular for creating decentralized gaming platforms. Developers utilize the API to create blockchain-powered games with in-game assets, currencies, and DeFi elements. Consequently, users of these platforms benefit from an immersive and engaging gaming experience.</p>
<h2 id="binance-smart-chain-maximizes-blockchain-potential">Binance Smart Chain Maximizes Blockchain Potential</h2>
<p>The Binance Smart Chain API offers numerous benefits to developers building powerful blockchain applications. It offers a comprehensive and easy-to-use interface with great performance, scalability, and seamless integration into the BSC ecosystem. The BSC API is thus a great choice for projects in various industries. The BSC API can help developers maximize their potential in blockchain and create applications to revolutionize the digital world.</p>
<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>The continued maturing of blockchain APIs will fundamentally change the attitudes toward the blockchain. It will be an important step in convincing the masses to adopt the blockchain as the base layer of Web3. One area that is still in need of further development is blockchain interoperability. However, there are already blockchain API projects working on this issue. Blockchain APIs will change how the world views blockchain technology in the coming years.</p>]]></content><author><name>Chaingateway</name></author><category term="Blockchain" /><category term="API" /><category term="Web3" /><category term="BSC" /><category term="Blockchain APIs" /><category term="DApps" /><category term="Smart Contracts" /><category term="Security" /><category term="Web3" /><category term="Web3 Future" /><category term="Decentralized Web3" /><category term="Binance Smart Chain API" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The role of Blockchain API in maximizing the potential of blockchain technology, with an example of the Binance Smart chain API.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/blog/2023/08/bitblade_illustration_of_blockchain_colors_like_image_style_lik.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/blog/2023/08/bitblade_illustration_of_blockchain_colors_like_image_style_lik.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Embracing The Future Chaingateway.io Teams Up With Forumpay To Accept</title><link href="/blog/embracing-the-future-chaingateway-io-teams-up-with-forumpay-to-accept/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Embracing The Future Chaingateway.io Teams Up With Forumpay To Accept" /><published>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/embracing-the-future-chaingateway.io-teams-up-with-forumpay-to-accept</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/embracing-the-future-chaingateway-io-teams-up-with-forumpay-to-accept/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://forumpay.com/">ForumPay</a>
<a href="https://chaingateway.io/">Chaingateway</a></p>

<p>In the fast-paced world of digital innovation, staying ahead of the curve is paramount. That’s why we are thrilled to announce the exciting partnership between <a href="https://chaingateway.io/">Chaingateway.io</a> and ForumPay. This collaboration marks a significant step forward in revolutionizing payment methods for our valued customers. As a leading provider of Blockchain API solutions, <a href="https://chaingateway.io/">Chaingateway.io</a> can now offer a seamless and secure way to accept cryptocurrencies as a payment method, thanks to the cutting-edge services provided by <a href="https://forumpay.com/">ForumPay</a>. In this article, we will explore how this partnership is reshaping the future of transactions in the blockchain ecosystem.</p>

<h2 id="the-power-of-blockchain-api-solutions">The Power of Blockchain API Solutions</h2>

<p>Before we delve into the exciting news, let’s take a moment to understand the vital role of Blockchain API solutions. At Chaingateway.io, we take pride in offering innovative and user-friendly solutions that empower businesses to integrate blockchains seamlessly into their applications. Our Blockchain API acts as a bridge, simplifying the process of connecting applications with the blockchain network. This opens up a world of possibilities, enabling digital asset management, smart contract execution, and decentralized identity verification.</p>

<h2 id="embracing-cryptocurrency-payments">Embracing Cryptocurrency Payments</h2>

<p>Recognizing the growing popularity and significance of cryptocurrencies, we are delighted to announce that <a href="https://chaingateway.io/">Chaingateway.io</a> is now embracing cryptocurrency payments for our payment plans. This decision was made possible through our partnership with ForumPay, a pioneering payment provider that specializes in processing cryptocurrency transactions securely and efficiently.</p>

<h2 id="seamless-and-secure-transactions">Seamless and Secure Transactions</h2>

<p>With the integration of ForumPay’s cryptocurrency payment gateway, our clients can now experience a seamless and secure payment process. By accepting cryptocurrencies, we streamline transactions, reduce processing time, and minimize transaction fees, ultimately enhancing the overall payment experience for both businesses and their customers.</p>

<h2 id="ensuring-top-notch-security">Ensuring Top-Notch Security</h2>

<p>Security is a top priority at Chaingateway.io, and with ForumPay’s advanced cryptographic protocols, we can ensure that all cryptocurrency transactions are conducted with the utmost security. The immutable nature of blockchain technology guarantees that sensitive financial data remains protected from potential threats, providing peace of mind to our valued clients.</p>

<h2 id="embracing-a-global-market">Embracing a Global Market</h2>

<p>One of the most exciting advantages of integrating cryptocurrency payments is the global accessibility it offers. Cryptocurrencies transcend geographical boundaries, enabling businesses to reach customers worldwide without the limitations of traditional payment systems. By partnering with Forumpay.com, we expand our reach and open up new opportunities in international markets, ensuring that businesses can grow and thrive on a global scale.</p>

<h2 id="a-future-forward-approach">A Future-Forward Approach</h2>

<p>At Chaingateway.io, we believe in future-proofing our business operations. The world of digital payments is evolving rapidly, and by accepting cryptocurrencies, we demonstrate our commitment to adopting innovative technologies that provide tangible benefits to our customers. Embracing ForumPay’s cryptocurrency payment solution reflects our dedication to staying at the forefront of the blockchain ecosystem.</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>The partnership between Chaingateway.io and Forumpay.com signifies a significant milestone in the world of blockchain and cryptocurrency. By accepting cryptocurrencies as a payment method for our payment plans, we are simplifying transactions and embracing the future of digital payments. Our collaboration with Forumpay.com ensures that our clients can enjoy a seamless, secure, and globally accessible payment experience, underpinned by the revolutionary potential of blockchain technology.</p>

<p>As we journey into the future, <a href="https://chaingateway.io/">Chaingateway.io</a> remains committed to providing cutting-edge solutions that empower businesses and developers to thrive in the digital age. With <a href="https://forumpay.com/">ForumPay’s</a> support, we are excited to embark on this new chapter, driving innovation and facilitating the widespread adoption of cryptocurrencies in the blockchain ecosystem. Together, we are forging a path towards a more connected, secure, and inclusive financial landscape.</p>]]></content><author><name>Chaingateway</name></author><category term="Blockchain" /><category term="API" /><category term="Web3" /><category term="Blockchain APIs" /><category term="DApps" /><category term="Smart Contracts" /><category term="Security" /><category term="Web3" /><category term="Web3 Future" /><category term="Decentralized Web3" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chaingateway.io partners with ForumPay, offering innovative Blockchain API solutions to enable seamless and secure cryptocurrency payments, revolutionizing the future of transactions in the blockchain ecosystem.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/blog/2023/08/embracing_the_future.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/blog/2023/08/embracing_the_future.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Level Up Your Crypto Yourney Chaingateway Unveils Rpc Api Beta</title><link href="/blog/level-up-your-crypto-yourney-chaingateway-unveils-rpc-api-beta/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Level Up Your Crypto Yourney Chaingateway Unveils Rpc Api Beta" /><published>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/blog/level-up-your-crypto-yourney-chaingateway-unveils-rpc-api-beta</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/level-up-your-crypto-yourney-chaingateway-unveils-rpc-api-beta/"><![CDATA[<p>In July we have several updates and improvements for our Chaingateway api. Check out what changed in our latest blog post!</p>

<p>Greetings, Chaingateway.io users!</p>

<p>I am thrilled to share some exciting updates and announcements with you regarding our latest developments. At Chaingateway.io, we are constantly striving to enhance your blockchain experience, and today, I want to introduce you to our new offerings. Join me as we explore the world of blockchain APIs and the incredible potential they hold.</p>

<h2 id="1-rpc-api-beta-elevating-security-and-functionality">1. RPC API BETA: Elevating Security and Functionality</h2>
<p>We are excited to unveil our RPC API BETA, now available for all blockchains! With this release, we have implemented enhanced security measures, ensuring a safer environment for developers. While we have removed certain functions, fret not! You can find the corresponding API calls in our comprehensive documentation, accessible at https://chaingateway.io/docs/. If you have specific function requests, please reach out to our support team at support@chaingateway.io. We value your input and will evaluate each request for potential approval.</p>

<h2 id="2-amplifying-growth-through-product-hunt--trustpilot-ratings">2. Amplifying Growth through Product Hunt &amp; Trustpilot Ratings</h2>
<p>Your feedback is invaluable to us! To show our appreciation and encourage your participation, we have exciting rewards for your ratings on renowned platforms such as Product Hunt and Trustpilot. As a free user, for each rating you provide, you will receive a one-month Pro Subscription. For our esteemed paid users, we have a special treat: a €49 coupon for every rating submitted. Your honest reviews play a pivotal role in our growth, and we sincerely thank you for your ongoing support. Simply provide your ratings using the following links:
Product Hunt: https://www.producthunt.com/products/chaingateway-io/reviews
TrustPilot: https://uk.trustpilot.com/review/chaingateway.io</p>

<h2 id="3-crypto-payment-gateway-partnership-welcoming-forumpaycom">3. Crypto Payment Gateway Partnership: Welcoming ForumPay.com</h2>
<p>We are delighted to announce our strategic partnership with ForumPay.com, a leading crypto payment gateway. This collaboration enables you to pay for your Chaingateway.io subscription using a wide range of cryptocurrencies, including Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, Litecoin, Ether, DASH, XRP, and USDT. By embracing the versatility of digital currencies, we aim to facilitate seamless and secure transactions within the blockchain ecosystem. Experience the freedom of choice and take advantage of the expanded payment options now available to you.</p>

<h2 id="4-empowering-users-with-the-referral-program">4. Empowering Users with the Referral Program</h2>
<p>Our community is the driving force behind our success. To foster growth and engagement, we are thrilled to introduce our referral program. As a Chaingateway.io user, you now have the opportunity to earn 20% of the plan fees paid by customers you refer. By inviting others to join our platform, not only do you expand our community, but you also enjoy the benefits of increased earnings. Stay connected with your referrals and track your earnings conveniently through our user-friendly referral program dashboard at https://app.chaingateway.io/referrals.</p>

<h2 id="5-important-change-updating-webhook-ip-addresses">5. Important Change: Updating Webhook IP Addresses</h2>
<p>To further enhance our services, we are implementing an important change to our Webhook IP addresses. We kindly request that you promptly update your whitelists to ensure uninterrupted service. Please make note of the following new IP addresses:</p>

<p>45.157.178.59
202.61.196.255
89.58.42.170
2a03:4000:66:e7f:4812:b0ff:fe69:65d5
2a03:4000:59:c07:e43e:76ff:fe25:35af
2a03:4000:4b:a2c:94bb:2dff:fed7:86e3</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion:</h2>
<p>At Chaingateway.io, we are committed to revolutionizing your blockchain experience. With the introduction of our RPC API BETA, we have strengthened security and expanded functionality. We value your feedback and appreciate your ratings on Product Hunt and Trustpilot. Through our partnership with ForumPay.com, we have diversified our payment options to accommodate various cryptocurrencies. Our referral program empowers you to be a catalyst for growth while reaping the rewards. Finally, remember to update your Webhook IP addresses to ensure uninterrupted services. Together, let’s unlock the immense potential of blockchain APIs and embrace the ever-evolving world of cryptocurrency.</p>

<p>Thank you for being a part of the Chaingateway.io community!</p>

<p>Warm regards,
The Chaingateway.io Team</p>]]></content><author><name>Chaingateway</name></author><category term="Blockchain" /><category term="API" /><category term="Web3" /><category term="Blockchain APIs" /><category term="DApps" /><category term="Smart Contracts" /><category term="Security" /><category term="Web3" /><category term="Web3 Future" /><category term="Decentralized Web3" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In July we have several updates and improvements for our Chaingateway api. Check out what changed in our latest blog post!]]></summary></entry></feed>